## **DINARA IGIMBAYEVA**

## igimbayevadinara@gmail.com | 917-684-6357 | New York, NY 10029

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced, knowledgeable and performance driven professional with strong analytical and supervisory skills and an excellent 10+ year record in managing diversified portfolios of mixed-use and luxury multi-property assets.

Strengths include in-depth understanding of day-to-day property operations including maintenance, compliance, financial and legal aspects of real estate management.

Personal skills include quick learning, critical thinking and problem solving, excellent work ethics and customer service. Strong analytical and supervisory skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Freestone Property Group | New York, NY

July 2022 - Present

# Head of Compliance

Dec 2022 - Present

- Responsible for filing annual rent registrations, DHCR due diligence and lease audits, rent overcharges and rent reduction compliance; MCI/IAI and sub-rehab, J51/421a exit registrations. Initial Rent Registrations. Filing RPIEs; Compliance with EHV/Section 8 and other vouchers, Scrie/Drie.
- Oversees HPD, DOB, FDNY, DEP, DOT violation removal, certification, hearings; Dismissal Inspections, Penalty waivers, closing out legacy permits and application for dispositions, refinancing and escrow holds.
- Oversees Local Law compliance, including but not limited to lead, mold, gas, energy efficiency, boiler, elevator, fire suppression system, fuel storage, fire extinguisher, RPZ, facade inspections, including timely affirmations of corrections.
- Oversees HPD, and DHCR litigations, negotiating with City collection agencies on legacy overdue defaulted violations and penalties.
- Actively involved in creating and troubleshooting SOPs and Workflows pertaining to Compliance, Violations, KPIs improvement and Interdepartmental Collaborations (Cross-Team Processes).
- Training Completed Leadership Communication, Coaching and Performance, Goal Setting and KPI Accountability, Creating a Culture of feedback, Delegating for Success.
- Class 1 DOB Filing rep course successfully completed in 2019 and 2022 to stay on top of DOB code changes.

## Senior Property Manager

**July 2022 – Dec 2022** 

- Manage day to day operations of a multi-property mixed use portfolio of 1200+ luxury and value add units, including overseeing maintenance, turnovers, and capital improvement projects.
- Ensure tenant retention and satisfaction, timely renewals and/or seamless move outs, turnovers.
- Ensure commercial tenants' compliance with the lease provisions, insurance and city codes including commercial space alterations oversight.
- Manage delinquencies, AR/AP, increasing NOI and reducing operational costs. Budget reviews, analyzing and explaining variances.
- Provide support during acquisitions and dispositions, refinancing, bank, insurance and environmental inspections. Compliance with post inspection recs.
- DOB, DHCR due diligence.
- Manage delinquencies, rent demands and petitions, overseeing holdovers, collections, etc. Actively involved in creating Delinquency and Legal workflow for PM teams.
- Manage compliance with City codes, violations removal, overseeing Capital improvements and Sub-rehabs, equipment installation, sign off, registrations and maintenance.
- Onboard new vendors, negotiating contracts, creating preferred vendor tracking system, ensuring vendors Insurance complies with the Company requirements.
- Bid out jobs/leveling, ensuring timely and cost-efficient project completion.
- Creating stream of periodic reports including vacancy, renewals, delinquency, collections, AP, unit turn, maintenance, lead compliance, violation corrections, periodic portfolio and staff KPIs.
- Heavily involved in developing and implementing operational processes, procedures and workflows, developing interdepartmental procedures. Hiring, training and oversight of staff.

- Managing day to day operations of a multi-property mixed-use portfolio of 700+ units, serving as a direct liaison between the Management team and the Property owners, including monthly, quarterly, end of year performance reporting;
- Responsibilities include oversight of maintenance, leasing, renewal and accounting departments, troubleshooting
- existing deficiencies, brainstorming improvements and creating operational procedures to ensure smooth and
- efficient performance;
- Managing compliance with city codes, DHCR, Section 8, including ensuring proper filings, correction of
- violations with all Departments and attending ECB/OATH hearings;
- Managing Collections, delinquencies, AR/AP, researching new streams of revenue and increasing value of the
- asset while reducing operational costs, increasing NOI. Managing Legal caseload for a timely and efficient
- resolution.
- Ensuring Commercial Tenants' compliance with the Lease provisions, insurance and city codes including
- commercial space alterations oversight.
- On/Off boarding properties during the acquisitions and dispositions, DHCR due diligence, financial reporting and
- GL audits;
- Overseeing MCI / IAI projects including Compliance with DHCR regulations. First Rent and Exit Registrations.
- Creating stream of periodic reports: vacancy, delinquency, collections, AR/AP, unit turn, maintenance, etc
- Compliance, Violation correction etc. Overseeing staff of 12.

# OvCo Realty LLC | New York, NY

Aug 2015 – July 2021

## **Property Manager**

- In charge of daily operations of a portfolio of 400+ residential/commercial tenants. Responsibilities include but not limited to addressing tenant inquiries, complaints and maintenance requests.
- Oversee renovations and capital improvements, maintenance and compliance in accordance with the City
  codes; serving as a direct liaison with vendors and/or contractors.
- Prepare and execute commercial and residential leases, renewals, assignments and releases; oversee marketing and renewals to maximize occupancy and retention.
- Represent ownership in ECB hearings and housing court; in charge of compliance with all city agencies and departments, as well as compliance with the insurance requirements; purchasing, payroll, scheduling, supervising and training staff of 25+ employees.

## Central Park Apartments | New York, NY

#### Assistant Property Manager

July 2011 – Aug 2013

- Assist tenants with inquiries; showings, credit checks, rentals and leasing; rent collections, GL, invoicing, maintaining filing system, managing correspondence.
- Address and follow up on tenants' complaints.
- Maintain work order and housekeeping systems.
- Handle tenants move in and outs, including sec. deposit refunds. rent rolls, monthly reports on revenue/ loss.
- Maintain tenant files, databases and invoices to ensure timely rent collection and/or late fee assessing, accurate rent prorating, on time move outs or extensions.
- Monthly and annual supplies inventory and restocking.
- Assist Property Manager with overseeing smooth business operations.
- Supervising staff of 5 employees.

# **EDUCATION**

#### KIMEP | Almaty, Kazakhstan

MA Financial Analysis - 2006-2008

### Kostanay State University | Kostanay, Kazakhstan

Professional Degree (BS+MS) in Electrical Engineering 2001-2006

#### **SOFTWARE**